LENIN GARCIA | 3D Animator

legcdesign@gmail.com | Tel. 787-943-3433

San Juan, Puerto Rico

www.linkedin.com/in/leningarcia https://vimeo.com/leningarcia

SUMMARY

Highly skilled 3D Animator with 10+ years of experience creating and animating diverse characters for mobile and PC games. Advanced proficiency in rigging, character integration and in developing tools that optimize animation workflows. Fluent in both artistic and technical collaboration, with a proven track record of delivering exceptional animations that enhance gameplay and storytelling.

EXPERIENCE

Senior 3D Animator | Rigger

SRG Studios (Hybrid)

Feb 2014 - May 2024

San Juan, Puerto Rico

- Contributed to the development of over 10 released mobile games, a PC game and 50+ tested prototypes, including popular titles like Champion Shift, Jaws.IO, and Ink Inc., which collectively garnered over 250 million downloads.
- Animated a diversity of characters, including bipeds, quadrupeds, creatures and robots, ensuring high-quality fluid motion.
- Rigged and integrated characters into the game engine, meeting artistic and technical requirements.
- Collaborated closely with design, VFX and art teams, to conceptualize and develop animations aligned with game objectives.
- Optimized the animation workflow with custom Python tools, increasing team efficiency.

3D Animator | Rigger

Easley-Dunn Games | Remote

Oct 2009 - Feb 2014

- Animated and rigged biped and quadruped characters for indie game projects.
- Designed user interface and created cinematics for trailers, enhancing marketing efforts.
- Worked with a remote team, efficiently meeting project goals and deadlines.

EDUCATION

Associate of Arts (AA) in Advanced Character Animation **Animation Mentor** 2007 - 2009

Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA) in Graphic Design Atlantic University 2003 - 2005

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Fluent in English and Spanish Available for relocation and remote opportunities

TOOLS

Maya MotionBuilder Blender **Unreal Engine** Unity Spine

SKILLS

3D Animation **Kevframe Animation** Mocap Editing Creature Animation Rigging Blueprint Scripting Python Tool Development Team Leadership Project Management

GAME DEVELOPMENT INITIATIVE

- Organized Game Jams and educational events
- Leadership roles in the local IGDA chapter
- Fostering community engagement in game development.

EXTENDED EDUCATION

Primitive Planning to Polish 2024 Stefan Iverson

Motion Capture For Games 2024 Harvey Newman

MotionBuilder Workshop 2023 iAnimate - Brent George

Dynamic Action Workshop 2023 Animawarriors - Stephen Eusebio

Facial Acting Workshop 2022 Animawarriors - Kevin Nguyen

Creature: Fight or Flight 2014 Animation Mentor - Jean-Denis Haas